{"tossups": [{"question": "Mary Birdsall bought a publication from this woman titled<em> The Lily</em> in which she once wrote\u201cIntemperance is the great foe to [women\u2019s] peace and happiness.\u201d This woman inspired Mary Gove Nichols to draft a document against Parisian styles. This woman promoted the \u201chealth, comfort, and usefulness\u201d of Libby Miller\u2019s design, which was displayed at the Seneca Falls Convention and took the form of a \u201cTurkish Dress.\u201d An 1851 \u201ccraze\u201d was sparked by, for ten points, what suffragette whose name was quickly attached to a style of divided, pant-like dress?", "answer": "Amelia<b> Bloomer</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This composer changed his surname so that he could serve with the YMCA during World War I. He reused the finale of his Second Suite for Military Band, \u201cFantasia on the Dargason,\u201d in his<em> St. Paul\u2019s</em> <em>Suite</em>. A patriotic hymn by Cecil Spring Rice named \u201cI Vow To Thee, My Country\u201d was set to<em> Thaxted</em>, which was taken from a suite by this man with movements subtitled \u201cThe Bringer of War\u201d and \u201cThe Bringer of Jollity.\u201d For ten points, name this English composer who depicted Mars and Jupiter in<em> The</em> <em>Planets</em>.", "answer": "Gustav (von)<b> Holst</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "A subset of this system co-named for Gardner and Salinas allows it to incorporate scientific notation, and the Antoine notation is used to represent numbers in this system. This system was an improvement upon one developed for Napoleon\u2019s army by Charles Barbier; that system was night writing. The Grade 2 variety is the most commonly used English type of this system, which was developed by a man who suffered an accident with an awl as a child. For ten points, name this writing system of raised dots used by the blind.", "answer": "<b> braille</b> writing Page 1", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "This man discussed the two halves of Barack Obama\u2019s private and public goals in his book<em> Obama and</em> <em>The Empire</em>. This leader published the newspaper<em> The Accuser</em> while leading a group simply called The Movement, after which he planned an attack on the Moncada Barracks. This leader deposed Fulgencio Batista in a revolution, during which he worked alongside his brother Raul. For ten points, name this longtime leader of communist Cuba who passed away in 2016.", "answer": "Fidel<b> Castro</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The planners of this event were influenced by an incendiary letter from the doctor Cornelius Rhoads and wished to avenge Pedro Campos\u2019 failed revolution of October 30. Donald Birdzell was struck in the knee during this event, while Leslie Coffelt was mortally wounded. The target of this event had been temporarily moved to the Blair House thanks to ongoing renovations at the White House. Oscar Collazo and Griselio Torresola carried out, for ten points, what 1950 event in which Puerto Rican nationalists targeted the sitting president?", "answer": "<b> attempted assassination</b> of Harry<b> Truman</b> (accept<b> attack on Truman</b> or similar phrasings that don\u2019t imply Truman died; do not accept or prompt on \u201cassassination of Truman,\u201d because he didn\u2019t die)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The inventor of this weapon earlier designed the first double action hemp break. John Henry Parker got a nickname inspired by these weapons, which he used to defend San Juan Hill during the Spanish-American War. Twelve of these weapons were deployed at the Siege of Petersburg. The ten caliber type of this hand-cranked weapon can fire up to 400 rounds a minute. For ten points, name these rapidly firing proto-machine guns that were prominently used in the Civil War and named for their American inventor.", "answer": "<b> Gatling</b> guns (prompt on machine gun before mentioned; do not accept or prompt on semi-or fully-automatic guns)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man gave his sister Anna in marriage to Vladimir I in exchange for the Chersonesos military base in the Crimea. This man was ambushed at the Gates of Trajan after successfully relieving Sofia from siege. After his greatest success, this man allegedly blinded 99 out of every 100 prisoners he took, a sight that made rival king Samuel die of shock. For ten points, name this winner of the Battle of Kleidion, a Byzantine emperor known as the \u201cBulgar-slayer.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Basil II</b> (or<b> Basil the Bulgar Slayer</b> before mentioned; accept<b> Basileios II</b>,<b> Basil the Porphyrogenitus</b>, or<b> Basil the Young</b>; prompt on Basil) (10) Nearly 1,500 of these objects are held at a museum in Marikina. After a 1992 political upheaval, hundreds of these objects were moved out of the basement of the Malacanang Palace. Upon the opening of a museum for these objects, their original owner remarked \u201cthey went into my closets looking for skeletons, but thank God, all they found were\u201d these objects. For ten points, name this collection of luxury fashion items amassed by the \u201cIron Butterfly\u201d of the Philippines, who wore most of the hundreds of pairs of them. ANSWER: Imelda<b> Marcos\u2019 shoes</b> (prompt on partial answers, like \u201cshoes\u201d or \u201cImelda\u2019s wardrobe\u201d) Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "At this battle, the winning side assembled a line of 50 artillery pieces between Dill and Tilghman branches. In this battle, a march toward River Road was conducted by Lew Wallace to avoid facing the enemy from the rear. After facing heavy casualties on one day during this battle, the Union commander said \u201cLick em\u2019 tomorrow, though.\u201d Albert Sidney Johnston was killed during this battle, in which Union forces defended an encampment called Pittsburg Landing. For ten points, name this 1862 Civil War victory for Grant in Tennessee.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Shiloh</b> (accept Battle of<b> Pittsburg Landing</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A Japanese version of this institution called the Ooku was created by Tokugawa Hidetada. Leaders of another of these institutions held either the title of Haseki or Valide. According to a probably fabricated legend, the Yongle Emperor killed 2800 members of one of these institutions to suppress a scandal. This term generally refers to a reserved domestic space, but has taken on the connotation of a brothel. For ten points, give this term for the quarters of the wives and concubines of imperial Ottoman rulers.", "answer": "<b> harem</b> (accept<b> seraglio</b>; accept<b> zenanna</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This city was the site of a brief coup known as the<em> Speckputsch</em>. This city\u2019s Margravial Opera House was built for Margrave Frederick, who ruled a principality named for Brandenburg and this city. Originally, performances of<em> Parsifal</em> were only allowed within this city\u2019s Festival Hall; that hall, sponsored by Mad King Ludwig, was the site of the premiere of<em> Der Ring des Nibelungen</em>. For ten points, name this Bavarian town which hosts a festival each year devoted to performing the works of Richard Wagner.", "answer": "<b> Bayreuth</b> [bye-royt]", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "At the end of this novel, the protagonist feels \u201cintegrated\u201d after his horse tramples his leg. An operation to blow up a bridge in this novel is nearly ruined when the detonators are stolen. The execution of fascist sympathizers in Pilar\u2019s village in this novel parallels a real life massacre in the city of Ronda. The protagonist of this novel is a member of the International Brigades and works for a Republican guerrilla unit under the leadership of Pablo. For ten points, name this novel about Robert Jordan\u2019s service during the Spanish Civil War, a work by Ernest Hemingway.", "answer": "<b> For Whom the Bell Tolls</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "A siege of this state\u2019s capital was carried out by the Pechenegs during their westward migration. The state\u2019s collapse led to the rise of Galicia-Volhynia and Vladimir-Suzdal and began after the Battle of the Kalka River, which it lost to the Mongols. Yaroslav the Wise led this state in the 11th century, and it was founded by Oleg the Seer, who moved its capital from Novgorod. The Rurikid dynasty led, for ten points, what precursor state to modern Russia?", "answer": "Kievan<b> Rus</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>One side in this war was forced to abandon aiding a Jacobite uprising after a storm off the Galician coast turned its fleet back. During this war, General Villasur was defeated by the Pawnee while attempting to curb French settlement in Nebraska. This war began after</b> <b>Philip V violated the Treaty of (+)</b> <b>Utrecht by claiming the French throne after Louis</b> <b>XIV\u2019s death. Sardinia was transferred to Savoy as part of the 1720 Treaty of (*)</b> The Hague, ending this war. For ten points, name this war in which Spain unsuccessfully fought a namesake alliance of Great Britain, France, the Holy Roman Empire, and the Dutch Republic.", "answer": "War of the<b> Quadruple Alliance</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This word titles a 1938 film by Leni Riefenstahl that features footage of the first torch relay. A \u201cModern\u201d work of this title features a man in a brown coat on the right leaning on a purple slope and looking away from the viewer at the title figure; that work is by (+) Paul Cezanne. Another artwork of this name appears to feature a</b><em><b> demi-mondaine</b></em><b>, based on her pearl earrings, the Oriental shawl she lies on, and the orchid in her hair; that apparent prostitute lies on a bed, looks at the viewer, and is attended by a (*) </b> black servant. For ten points, give this common name shared by a masterpiece of \u00b4Edouard Manet [man-ay].", "answer": "<b> Olympia</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Those notes, which include a point to\u201ckeep Anna Chennault working on SVN,\u201d were taken by this man\u2019s future Chief of Staff, (+) H.R. Haldeman, and prove that this man tried to hurt Hubert Humphrey\u2019s presidential campaign by sabotaging peace negotiations in (*)</b> Vietnam. For ten points, name this man who, shortly after, won the 1968 election and expanded the Vietnam War as the successor to Lyndon Johnson.", "answer": "Richard<b> Nixon</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Displays at this event included a barometer that based observations on the movement of leeches and Frederick Bakewell\u2019s early version of a fax machine. An object known as the</b> <b>\u201cMountain of Light\u201d that had once been owned by (+)</b> <b>Nader Shah was displayed during</b> <b>this event. The man who devised the first Christmas card, Henry Cole, helped organize this event. The Koh-i-Noor Diamond was on display during this event, which was attended by writers like George (*) </b> Eliot and Charles Dickens. Prince Albert helped plan, for ten points, what 1851 exhibition in London, held in a magnificent plate glass building?", "answer": "<b> Crystal Palace</b> Exhibition (accept The<b> Great Exhibition</b> of the Works of Industry of All Nations) (8) <b>This man\u2019s presence on the first board of trustees at Jane Addams\u2019 Hull House</b> <b>reflected his interest in the formation of a democratic community. This man\u2019s work in</b> <b>epistemology,</b><em><b> Knowing and the Known</b></em><b>, was co-written with Arthur (+)</b> <b>Bentley. This</b> <b>man\u2019s \u201cinstrumentalist\u201d philosophy was similar to the American school of pragmatism, and he founded the Laboratory School of (*)</b> Chicago to promote experiential learning. This philosopher argued that education should be seen as a continuation of civil society. For ten points, name this liberal education advocate and author of<em> Democracy and Education</em>. ANSWER: John<b> Dewey</b> Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}